

**DharaniPrasad**Programmer Analyst

Total Exp - 1 year

© 0919642277372

☑ Dharani.Prasad@cognizant.com

Chennai Tamil Nadu

Skills

Skill Summary

Amazon Web Services

Banking Operations

BFS

Java 8

**ANSI SQL** 

**JDBC** 

al

ш

Core Java

Supply Chain Management

**Technology Concepts** 

Domain-Industry Knowledge

An independent and self-motivated professional with proven ability in analytical skills and experienced in developing web application using full stack and Data Science projects with DS and Algorithms. I have also participated in various competitions of competitive programming. Recognized by clients, colleagues, and peers as a personable, dedicated performer who demonstrates innovation, communication, and teamwork. Understanding client requirements during meetings to ensure quality, timely project completion.

#### **Work Experience**

### Cognizant Experience

Broadridge-ClientOnboarding | Developer- 8 Months (Apr 2021 - Dec 2021)

### Project Description

Client Onboarding (COB) platform is a unified interface for the FAs/CSAs and operations users providing ability to create/maintain Client data, Account information and relationships. It addresses the overall Customer Data Management needs. This platform is accessed by FAs/CSAs/Ops Users and integrates with in-house applications of UBS like Advisory Toolkit, OLS Desktop, Service Works, Document Management System (DMS), Client Relationship Database (CRDB) and vendor applications of UBS like NexJ. Lexis Nexis and Equifax are the third party / external applications that the platform feeds data into.

### Roles & Responsibilities

• Involved in CQRS implementation using AWS • Involved in product designing using Micro Services • Involved in the requirement gathering meetings with client. • Developing AWS resources to align with CQRS • Having good knowledge in AWS components such as Lambda, SQS, SNS, S3, DynamoDB, RDS, EC2, IAM, SSM, Glue, VPC and Security Groups. • Data Transformation using PySpark in AWS Glue • Daily meetings with Onsite PM for requirement gathering and implementation plan. • Attend the Scrum call on every day for status report. • Status report to Project Manager

### Skills used for Broadridge-ClientOnboarding

Amazon Web Services III Banking Operations Java 8 III BFS

#### Other Experience

Remedy Acknowledgement System | Developer - 3 Months (Jan-2021 - Mar 2021)

#### Project Description

The Remedy Acknowledgement system is a ticketing Helpdesk application that is built as a ticket delivery tool in a system and to facilitate and can be used as a communication channel by the IT Department with users, in terms of supporting the provision and use of facilities related to systems and technology evaluate problems that often occur.

### Roles & Responsibilities

• Involved in the requirement gathering meetings with client. • Developing End to End application. • Interacting with PM to update the status of the project. • Integrated application with relational Database using hibernate. • Implemented project in MVC (Model View Controller) Pattern. • Deployed Application using cloud services. • Involved in product designing using Micro Services. • Involved in Exploring new Technical concepts for integrating to this project. • Lead the team to deliver the System Integrations.

# [ ] Skills used for Remedy Acknowledgement System

ANSISQL III JDBC III Core Java III Java 8 III

Accident Risk Prediction using Data Science | Developer - 9 Months (Jan-2021 - Oct 2021)

# Project Description

Artificial Intelligence (AI) is already changing the world across. The Machine Learning algorithms that enable AI, are taking control of a large part of the daily lives, without most of them even realizing it. By algorithmically deriving real-time information from raw data is capable of training the machine to predict risks involved in any given transportation activity, on which key decisions are then based. To provide accurate predictions prior to transport scheduling, machine learning techniques are used. The final model will warn us regarding the vehicles current health. We have used Deep Learning models to train the model and detect where there is a tyre in a image and classify the present condition of the tyre. To know if the tyre tread is damaged or not. The models reads the image clearly and using the trained data it identifies the percentage of damage of the tyre.

# Roles & Responsibilities

• Involved in Data Mining tasks for creation of Dataset in Machine Learning model Development. • Involved in Data Preprocessing Techniques for making the data useful for creating Machine Learning models • Owned and executed end to end multiple data science projects • Translate product requirements into analytical requiremnets/specification, design and develop required functionality. • Leveraged technology to automate daily operational activities. • Involved in creating various regression and classification algorithms by using various sklearn libraries such as Linear Regression, Decision Trees, Naïve Baye's • Involved in Machine Learning model Deployment in Company server, Google cloud and Heroku server • Involved in creating Machine Learning models for test A/B content which is useful for making better decisions regarding the products • Status report to Project Manager

# Skills used for Accident Risk Prediction using Data Science

Supply Chain Management Technology Concepts Domain-Industry Knowledge

# Career Highlights

Received Sapphire Award for the recognition of excellence in project.
 Mentored colleagues in Machine Learning
 Deployed a Machine Learning model on Live as an Intern with minimal support
 Deployed Remedy Acknowledgement
 Project during Cognizant Academy Training.

# Education

# Graduation

